<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analytics on Mr. Zeynalli&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/data-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analytics on Mr. Zeynalli&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:33:53 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/data-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of State Schools in Scotland: K-Means Clustering by Deprivation Rate and Pupils Quantity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/scottish_schools_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/scottish_schools_clustering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objective of this project is to conduct a comprehensive analysis of Scottish schools in order to derive valuable insights. The analysis includes clustering and descriptive analysis, taking into account factors such as deprivation rate and total number of pupils. Additionally, an interactive map of Scotland has been developed to visually represent the location of each school. The clustering model has categorized local authorities into three distinct clusters based on average pupil count and deprivation score. The map highlights areas predominantly occupied by schools facing high levels of deprivation. The aim is to assist charities or non-governmental organizations (NGOs) involved in projects supporting these school pupils. All data used in this analysis is publicly available and sourced from the Scottish Government website. The Postcodes.io API was utilized to gather latitude and longitude coordinates for each school based on their respective postcodes. The codes for clustering, visualizations, map generation, and API application can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrzeynalli/scotland_schools.git&#34;&gt;my GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. You are welcome to access and utilize the repository&amp;rsquo;s contents for personal or commercial purposes without seeking my consent. I hope you find this information enlightening and enjoyable to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Analytics: Analyzing clickstream of 160,000 visitors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web_analytics_clickstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web_analytics_clickstream/</guid>
      <description>This project is carried out by me for a university assignment. The dataset is a randomly generated visitor clickstream to a website of a company. All codes and explanations, along with the dataset, are present in my GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-capital UK Cities with High-tech Potential</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uk_cities_tech_potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uk_cities_tech_potential/</guid>
      <description>An analysis of non-capital UK cities with high-tech potential using Companies House API. A data analytics project that identifies decentralized tech hubs in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zondo Reports Text Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zondo_reports_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zondo_reports_analysis/</guid>
      <description>This project is carried out by me and my classmate under an assignment for one of my courses at the University of Edinburgh. The project received an A grade; all the coding and visualizations along with a mini report are shared on my GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
