<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Mr. Zeynalli&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Mr. Zeynalli&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 18:33:53 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of State Schools in Scotland: Map of Scotland with Schools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/scottish_schools_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/scottish_schools_map/</guid>
      <description>In this project, the objective is to conduct an analysis of Scottish schools in order to derive valuable insights. In a separate article, a clustering and descriptive analysis of schools based on their deprivation rate and total number of pupils was performed. The resulting model categorized local authorities into three distinct clusters based on their average pupil count and deprivation score. The present article showcases an interactive map that visually illustrates the areas predominantly occupied by schools facing high levels of deprivation. The intention behind this is to provide guidance to charities or non-governmental organizations engaged in projects aimed at assisting school pupils. All data utilized in this analysis is publicly available and sourced from the website of the Scottish Government. Furthermore, the Postcodes.io API was employed to gather the geographical coordinates (latitude and longitude) of each school based on their respective postcodes. The code for constructing the map, as well as an API application for retrieving external information, along with the datasets employed, can be found in the project’s GitHub repository. All materials within the repository are free to be utilized for personal and commercial purposes without requiring my consent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Web Crawler using Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/python_web_crawler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/python_web_crawler/</guid>
      <description>A guide on building a simple web crawler using Python, including a deep dive into web crawling concepts and practical implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Analytics: Analyzing clickstream of 160,000 visitors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web_analytics_clickstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web_analytics_clickstream/</guid>
      <description>This project is carried out by me for a university assignment. The dataset is a randomly generated visitor clickstream to a website of a company. All codes and explanations, along with the dataset, are present in my GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIFA23 Players Analysis: k-Means Clustering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fifa23_players_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fifa23_players_analysis/</guid>
      <description>This project is carried out by me independently. The dataset is obtained publicly from Kaggle. All codes and their explanations are stored in my GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zondo Reports Text Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zondo_reports_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 18:33:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zondo_reports_analysis/</guid>
      <description>This project is carried out by me and my classmate under an assignment for one of my courses at the University of Edinburgh. The project received an A grade; all the coding and visualizations along with a mini report are shared on my GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
